<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Everyday Statistics</title>
    <link>https://SamLeeBYU.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Everyday Statistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://SamLeeBYU.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Modeling with NCAA Field Goal Attempts and Percentages</title>
      <link>https://SamLeeBYU.github.io/2023/12/22/bayesian-modeling-ncaa-field-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://SamLeeBYU.github.io/2023/12/22/bayesian-modeling-ncaa-field-goals/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The NCAA Men’s Basketball tournament has been a well-known and highly anticipated sporting event since 1939 for not only the athletic aspects of the game, but also for the prediction of winning brackets. In the realm of sports analytics and statistical modeling, the question of replicating tournament outcomes has become an increasingly intriguing challenge. Although there are various covariates that contribute to whether a team wins or lose, we aim to utilize the Field Goal Attempts (FGA) data from the 2022 regular season to replicate the 2023 results of the tournament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Traffic Fines: Trends in Weather &amp; Air Quality - EDA</title>
      <link>https://SamLeeBYU.github.io/2023/12/16/byu-traffic-citations-eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://SamLeeBYU.github.io/2023/12/16/byu-traffic-citations-eda/</guid>
      <description>This project is part of a two-post series. See the first post here
All code and progress for this project is kept up to date at https://github.com/SamLeeBYU/BYUTrafficCitations.
Introduction Both private and public universities across the United Sates typically have university-specific parking service to enforce university parking regulations due to limited parking space supply. For the purposes of this analysis, we will analyze traffic citation data specific to my university, Brigham Young University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting a Causal Effect for COVID-19 Mortality on Per-County Housing Prices</title>
      <link>https://SamLeeBYU.github.io/2023/12/12/covid-mortality-effect-on-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://SamLeeBYU.github.io/2023/12/12/covid-mortality-effect-on-housing/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this analysis I seek to estimate the causal effect that 2020 COVID-19 mortality rates had on per-county housing prices in the United States in 2021. According to elementary economic theory, all else equal, when consumers of a good leave a market, demand decreases. This implies that prices decrease at every quantity demanded (Law of Demand). This theory may be grimly applied when we analyze COVID-19 mortality deaths from 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Traffic Fines: Trends in Weather &amp; Air Quality - Data Collection</title>
      <link>https://SamLeeBYU.github.io/2023/11/13/byu-traffic-citations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://SamLeeBYU.github.io/2023/11/13/byu-traffic-citations/</guid>
      <description>All code and progress for this project is kept up to date at https://github.com/SamLeeBYU/BYUTrafficCitations.
Introduction The idea for this project sparked when I received yet another parking citation from BYU during the spring semester of 2023. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I went to pay the citation where I realized BYU&amp;rsquo;s citation database [1] was scrapable. Though BYU hides certain citation-specific details for privacy purposes, the general information of every citation scraped is available for anyone with BYU credentials: Notable information such as the time of a citation, plate/vin number, and fine amount could all be parsed by iterating through a combination of citation numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Scraping Using Selenium: Best Practices and Example</title>
      <link>https://SamLeeBYU.github.io/2023/09/29/selenium-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://SamLeeBYU.github.io/2023/09/29/selenium-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this tutorial I will walk through the code used for a basic model that I used to scrape through the traffic citations database stored on the BYU server.
(Though the example is particularly directed towards BYU students, the structure and syntax of the example can be applied anywhere)
All code in this tutorial is posted on my Github here.
Through my experiences of trial and error and much headache of not being able to figure out why my code isn&amp;rsquo;t working, and by watching countless tutorials myself, I want to make this tutorial to demonstrate the best way I found to go about scraping data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
